[{"stepName": "Identify Motion of objects", "stepNumber": 1, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "How many moving objects are present?", "options": [1, 2, 0, 5], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 0, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "tobeshown": 1, "show1": [""], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "How many strings are there?", "options": [4, 0, 2, 5], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 0, "tobeshown": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "type": "advance", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}]}, {"stepName": "Write FBD equation for each Moving block", "stepNumber": 2, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block in the y-direction", "options": ["+T\u2081+40=0", "-T\u2081-40=0", "-T\u2081+40=0", "+T\u2081-40=0"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "+T\u2081-40=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "T\u2082: Tension in red string", "N\u2081: Normal between yellow block and Big block"], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for red block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on red block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2081 downwards", "T\u2081 upwards"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block in the y-direction", "options": ["+T\u2081+40=0", "-T\u2081-40=0", "-T\u2081+40=0", "+T\u2081-40=0"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2081, ", "Downward Forces: 40", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block in the y-direction", "options": ["-T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "+T\u2081-N\u2081-10=0", "+T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "-T\u2081-N\u2081-10=0"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "-T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "T\u2082: Tension in red string", "N\u2081: Normal between yellow block and Big block"], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "What is the direction of normal reaction on block 2 due to B?", "options": ["N1 perpendicular up", "N1 perpendicular down"], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0"], "type": "advance", "answer": 0, "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"]}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for yellow block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "answer": 2}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on yellow block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2081 upwards", "T\u2081 downwards"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"]}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on yellow block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2082 rightwards", "T\u2082 leftwards"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: T\u2081, ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block in the y-direction", "options": ["-T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "+T\u2081-N\u2081-10=0", "+T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "-T\u2081-N\u2081-10=0"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: N1, ", "Downward Forces: T\u2081, 10", "Rightward Forces: T\u2082, ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block in the x-direction", "options": ["+T\u2082=1a\u2081", "-T\u2082=1a\u2081"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "+T\u2082=1a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "T\u2082: Tension in red string", "N\u2081: Normal between yellow block and Big block"], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block in the x-direction", "options": ["+T\u2082=1a\u2081", "-T\u2082=1a\u2081"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: N1, ", "Downward Forces: T\u2081, 10", "Rightward Forces: T\u2082, ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2082=1a\u2081"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of blue block in the y-direction", "options": ["+20+T\u2082=2a\u2081", "+20-T\u2082=2a\u2081", "-20+T\u2082=2a\u2081", "-20-T\u2082=2a\u2081"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2082=1a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2082=1a\u2081", "+20-T\u2082=2a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "T\u2082: Tension in red string", "N\u2081: Normal between yellow block and Big block"], "showfcheading": ["Blue block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for blue block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2082=1a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2082=1a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Blue block"], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on blue block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2082 upwards", "T\u2082 downwards"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2082=1a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2082=1a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Blue block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of blue block in the y-direction", "options": ["+20+T\u2082=2a\u2081", "+20-T\u2082=2a\u2081", "-20+T\u2082=2a\u2081", "-20-T\u2082=2a\u2081"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2082=1a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2082, ", "Downward Forces: 20", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Blue block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2082=1a\u2081", "Blue block: +20-T\u2082=2a\u2081"]}]}, {"stepName": "Constraint Equations", "stepNumber": 3, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What is the constraint equation for red string?", "options": ["+a\u2081+a\u2081=0", "+a\u2081-a\u2081=0", "-a\u2081+a\u2081=0", "-a\u2081-a\u2081=0"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2082=1a\u2081", "Blue block: +20-T\u2082=2a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2082=1a\u2081", "Blue block: +20-T\u2082=2a\u2081", "-a\u2081+a\u2081=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["a\u2081: acceleration of red block in y-direction", "a\u2081y: acceleration of yellow block in y-direction", "a\u2081: acceleration of yellow block in x-direction", "a\u2081: acceleration of blue block in y-direction", "a\u2081y: acceleration of first pulley in y-direction", "a\u2081x: acceleration of first pulley in x-direction", "a\u2084y: acceleration of second pulley in y-direction", "a\u2084x: acceleration of second pulley in x-direction"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "What is the number of parts which change length in the red string?", "options": [5, 4, 2, 3], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2082=1a\u2081", "Blue block: +20-T\u2082=2a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2082=1a\u2081", "Blue block: +20-T\u2082=2a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": ["Red string"], "tobeshown": 0}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2081 for red string:", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2081", "-a\u2081"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2082=1a\u2081", "Blue block: +20-T\u2082=2a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2082=1a\u2081", "Blue block: +20-T\u2082=2a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2082 for red string:", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2081", "-a\u2081"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2082=1a\u2081", "Blue block: +20-T\u2082=2a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2082=1a\u2081", "Blue block: +20-T\u2082=2a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"]}, {"question": "What is the constraint equation for red string?", "options": ["+a\u2081+a\u2081=0", "+a\u2081-a\u2081=0", "-a\u2081+a\u2081=0", "-a\u2081-a\u2081=0"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2082=1a\u2081", "Blue block: +20-T\u2082=2a\u2081"], "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant", "l\u2081'' = -a\u2081", "l\u2082'' = +a\u2081"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"], "tobeshown": 0, "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2082=1a\u2081", "Blue block: +20-T\u2082=2a\u2081", "Red string: -a\u2081+a\u2081=0"], "type": "advance"}]}, {"stepName": "Final Answers", "stepNumber": 4, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What are the final accelerations, tensions and normal reactions?", "options": ["a\u2081= 6.67, a\u2081= -6.67, T\u2081= 40.0, T\u2082= 6.67, N\u2081= 50.0", "a\u2081= -6.67, a\u2081= -6.67, T\u2081= 6.67, T\u2082= -50.0, N\u2081= -40.0", "a\u2081= 6.67, a\u2081= -40.0, T\u2081= -6.67, T\u2082= -50.0, N\u2081= -6.67", "a\u2081= 6.67, a\u2081= -6.67, T\u2081= -50.0, T\u2082= -6.67, N\u2081= -40.0"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 0, "threejssubsubstep": 0, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2082=1a\u2081", "Blue block: +20-T\u2082=2a\u2081", "Red string: -a\u2081+a\u2081=0"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": [], "tobeshown": 1, "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2081, a\u2081, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-40=0", "Yellow block: -T\u2081+N\u2081-10=0", "Yellow block: +T\u2082=1a\u2081", "Blue block: +20-T\u2082=2a\u2081", "Red string: -a\u2081+a\u2081=0", "Final Answers: a\u2081= 6.67, a\u2081= -6.67, T\u2081= 40.0, T\u2082= 6.67, N\u2081= 50.0"]}]}]